?Are you ready, kids-
？你们准​​备好了吗，孩子们——
.KIDS: Aye, aye, Captain
.KIDS：是的，是的，队长
!I can't hear you-
！我听不到你说话-
.KIDS: Aye, aye, Captain
.KIDS：是的，是的，队长
THEME SONG: Oh, who lives in
?a pineapple under the sea
主题曲：哦，谁住在
？海底的菠萝
.Spongebob Squarepants
.海绵宝宝
,Absorbent, and yellow
.and porous is he
,吸水性,黄色
.他是多孔的
.Spongebob Squarepants
.海绵宝宝
If nautical nonsense
be something
如果航海废话
成为某物
you wish-- Spongebob
.Squarepants
你愿意——海绵宝宝
.方裤
Then flop on the deck
.and flop like a fish
然后扑倒在甲板上
.然后像鱼一样扑通扑通
.Spongebob Squarepants
.海绵宝宝
?Ready
？准备好
,Spongebob Squarepants
,海绵宝宝
.Spongebob Squarepants
.海绵宝宝
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[HUMMING]
[嗡嗡声]
.There we go-
.我们走了-
Hey, Spongebob, I got all the
leaves raked-- Spongebob, what
嘿，海绵宝宝，我得到了所有
树叶倾斜——海绵宝宝，什么
?are all these leaves doing here
？这些叶子都在这里干吗？
You said you were
?gonna rake 'em
你说你是
？要耙他们
.I am raking the leaves-
.我正在耙树叶-
But they're still-
.all over the ground
但他们仍然——
.遍布地面
.Sandy, I can't rake any faster-
.桑迪，我不能耙得更快了-
.These are big leaves
.这些是大叶子
And they keep breaking
.in to more leaves
他们不断打破
.进入更多叶子
Then go scrape the-
.salt lick or something
然后去刮——
.盐舔什么的
We gotta get this stuff
.done before it's too late
我们必须得到这个东西
.在为时已晚之前完成
What's the big-
?rush anyway, Sandy
有什么大的——
？无论如何，桑迪
.I told you, Spongebob-
.我告诉过你了，海绵宝宝-
.I'm hibernating next week
.我下周要冬眠
?Hibernating-
？冬眠-
?What's that
？那是什么
It's when I go to sleep-
.for the whole winter
就在我睡觉的时候——
.整个冬天
?Can I do that-
？我可以这样做吗-
.No, silly-
.不，愚蠢的-
.It's a mammalian thing
.这是哺乳动物的事情
Sandy, you may not have-
.noticed, but I is 100% mammal
桑迪，你可能没有-
.注意到了，但我是 100% 哺乳动物
Enough chitter-
.chatter, Spongebob
闲聊够了——
.chatter, 海绵宝宝
.We don't have much time left
.我们剩下的时间不多了
?Why, Sandy-
？为什么，桑迪-
When does your
?carboration begin
你的什么时候
?碳化开始
!In one week-
！一周后——
But Sandy, that only gives-
--us-- one, two, three
但是桑迪，这只会让——
--我们-- 一、二、三
[GASPS]
[喘气]
.168 more hours of play time--
.168 多小时的游戏时间--
!You're telling me-
！你是在告诉我——
.And there's still so much to do
.还有很多事情要做
.We gotta climb some things
.我们得爬一些东西
.Climb-
。爬-
.We gotta jump off of stuff-
.我们得跳下来-
.Jump-
。跳-
.We gotta ride-
.我们得骑-
.Ride-
。骑-
.I don't want to sleep yet-
.我还不想睡觉-
.Wait, Sandy-
.等等，桑迪-
.I can't burn carbs in my sleep-
.我无法在睡眠中燃烧碳水化合物-
?Sandy-
？沙-
?What-
？什么-
Sandy, I'm willing to-
sacrifice any of my time
桑迪，我愿意-
牺牲我的任何时间
that I haven't already
.sold to Mr. Krabs to you
我还没有
.卖给蟹老板给你
.Well, I'm glad, Spongebob-
.嗯，我很高兴，海绵宝宝-
Because for the seven
days, it's going
因为对于七
天，正在进行
to be you, me, and
.these sweat bands
成为你、我和
.这些吸汗带
!Yee-haw
！呀呀
.Uh, I can explain-
.呃，我可以解释一下-
I'm hotter than a-
.hickory smoked sausage
我比一个更热-
.山核桃熏香肠
!Woohoo
！哇哦
Maybe, if we sing that-
.song, he'll come to life
也许，如果我们唱——
.歌曲，他会复活
?Ready
？准备好
BOTH: Oh, there
--once was a tin man
两人：哦，那里
——曾经是一个铁皮人
Life's as extreme as-
!you want to make it, hoo
生活就像极端一样——
！你想成功吗，呼
.Maybe we didn't sing it right-
.也许我们唱得不对-
.Yeah-
。是的-
.Hoo, what a workout
.呼，多么锻炼啊
I'm gonna be feeling
.this tomorrow
我会感觉
.这个明天
.Ow
.噢
I gotta say I'm impressed-
.with you, Spongebob
我得说我印象深刻——
.和你在一起，海绵宝宝
You're making this the best
.pre-hibernation week ever
你正在使这成为最好的
.冬眠前一周
Well, I'd better get home-
before Gary chews up the sofa
好吧，我最好回家了——
在加里咀嚼沙发之前
.again
。再次
[SIGHS]
[叹气]
[GASPS]
[喘气]
.Goodnight, Gary-
.晚安，加里-
[SNORING]
[打鼾]
!Ah-
！啊-
!Woohoohoo-
！呜呼呼——
Nothing like a refreshing
?morning dip, huh, Spongebob
没有什么比清爽
？早上泡个澡，嗯，海绵宝宝
?What happened to sleeping-
？睡觉怎么了-
Well, I'll be-
,asleep all winter
嗯，我会-
，睡了一整个冬天
.we only got three days for fun
.我们只有三天的时间玩
.Well, hurry now
.好吧，现在快点
The giant clams like
.to feed at this hour
巨型蛤蜊就像
.这个时间喂食
[GROANING]
[呻吟]
?Isn't this great
？这不是很棒吗
Yeah, I've never played-
.extreme jacks before
是啊，我没玩过——
.之前的极限杰克
OK, Spongebob, this-
.one's gonna be fun
好吧，海绵宝宝，这个——
.一个人会很有趣
We just whack each other
with these giant ear cleaners
我们只是互相殴打
有了这些巨大的耳朵清洁器
.till one of us falls off
.直到我们中的一个跌倒
--On your mark, get set
——各就各位，准备就绪
Sandy, are you-
sure we're supposed
桑迪，你是——
当然我们应该
?to be standing up here
？站在这里
!Go-
！去-
!Ah-
！啊-
.Come on, Spongebob-
.来吧，海绵宝宝-
We're going for a tandem
.ride through the park
我们要去串联
.骑车穿过公园
Gee, that sounds-
.safe-- I mean, fun
哎呀，这听起来——
.安全——我的意思是，有趣
.OK, I'm ready
.好的，我准备好了
[GASPING]
[喘气]
I thought you said we were-
.riding through the park, Sandy
我以为你说我们是-
.骑车穿过公园，桑迪
.I did, Spongebob-
.我做到了，海绵宝宝-
.The industrial park
.工业园区
This is where the
.real action is
这就是
.真正的行动是
.Come on, pedal
.来吧，踩踏板
.This part gets pretty technical
.这部分非常技术性
.Yee-haw
.呀呀
.Now for the speed course
.现在进入快速课程
.Hang on
。不挂断
.I hope we make it
.我希望我们能成功
!Ah-
！啊-
!I'm having fun too-
！我也玩得很开心-
.Wake up, slowpoke
.醒醒吧，慢吞吞的
.We're going fly fishing
.我们要去飞钓
[RIMSHOT]
[边缘射击]
SPONGEBOB (VOICEOVER): This
.squirrel's trying to kill me
海绵宝宝（画外音）：这个
.松鼠想杀我
Any more of these stunts and
.I'll be reduced to a puddle
任何更多的这些特技和
.我会变成一个水坑
Wait a minute, I gotta
.talk my way out of this
等一下，我得
.谈谈我的出路
Sandy, I think I need
.to tell you something
桑迪，我想我需要
.告诉你一件事
?What is it-
？这是什么-
Well, it's just that-
I'm feeling sort of-- I
嗯，只是这样——
我感觉有点——我
--just feel like maybe I need to
——只是觉得也许我需要
,Hold that thought, Spongebob-
cause it's time for a down home
，保持这个想法，海绵宝宝——
因为是时候回家了
favourite, find the hay
.in the needle stack
最喜欢的，找到干草
.在针栈中
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
.Ow, ow, ow, ow-
.呜呜呜-
.Ouch
。哎哟
?Did you find it-
？你找到了吗-
.Not yet-
。还没有-
Well, I'm going-
.to look over here
好吧，我要去——
.看这里
.You do that-
.你这样做-
.Found it, Spongebob-
.找到了，海绵宝宝-
.Come on, best two out of three
.来吧，三中最好的两个
.Gotta hide-
.得躲起来-
.Gotta hide
.必须躲起来
?Home
？家
.No, Gary can't keep a secret
.不，加里不能保守秘密
!Under a rock
！在岩石下
.It's so original
.太原始了
!SANDY: Spongebob
!桑迪：海绵宝宝
!Spongebob
！海绵宝宝
Where are you
?little square dude
你在哪里
？小方块家伙
[GASPS]
[喘气]
Spongebob's tie, and all
?his other little dressings
海绵宝宝的领带，还有所有
？他的其他小调料
But-- But he always
folds his clothes
但是——但是他总是
折叠他的衣服
before running
.around in the nude
跑步前
.裸体周围
Something terrible
.must've happened to him
可怕的事情
.一定发生在他身上
.All right, listen up, y'all
.好吧，听着，你们大家
.I'm rounding up a search party
.我正在围捕一支搜寻队
.Spongebob's gone missing
.海绵宝宝失踪了
.Man the lifeboats-
.驾驶救生艇-
.Alpha team, you search uptown-
.阿尔法小队，你搜索住宅区-
.Gold team searches downtown-
.黄金队在市中心搜索-
?Any questions
?有任何问题吗
.Gold team rules-
.金牌团队规则-
.SANDY: Now get moving
.SANDY：现在开始吧
[CROWD CLAMORING]
[人群喧闹]
.Someone look up there-
.有人抬头看-
.Put your dorsal fins into it
.把你的背鳍放进去
Come on, he can be anywhere
.in these sulphur fields
来吧，他可以在任何地方
.在这些硫磺矿区
!Hey, Spongebob-
！嘿，海绵宝宝-
Well, at least I still
.have my personality
嗯，至少我还是
.有我的个性
.Check in this here moist cave-
.检查一下这个潮湿的洞穴-
!CROWD: Spongebob
!人群：海绵宝宝
!Ah
！啊
.Status report-
.状态报告-
He's not in the-
.poison sea urchin cove
他不在——
.毒海胆湾
.Well, look again-
.好吧，再看看-
.He's not at the leech farm-
.他不在水蛭养殖场-
.Well, look again-
.好吧，再看看-
.He's not in my thoughts-
.他不在我的脑海里-
.Well, think again-
.好吧，再想一想-
Attention, Bikini
Bottom, the time
注意，比基尼
底下，时间
,has come to double
.no, triple our efforts
,已经翻倍了
.不，我们要加倍努力
?How about a break-
?休息一下怎么样-
.We've been at it for days
.我们已经研究了好几天了
.Think about the children-
.想想孩子们——
.That's a good idea-
.这是个好主意-
Use the children to
crawl into small places
利用孩子们
爬进小地方
.you couldn't normally reach
.你通常无法到达
.This is a load of barnacles-
.这是一堆藤壶-
.I heard that-
.我听说-
No one's going anywhere
.till we find Spongebob
没有人去任何地方
.直到我们找到海绵宝宝
.Oh, wait, uh, here is-
.哦，等等，呃，这是-
.That ain't Spongebob-
.那不是海绵宝宝-
.Spongebob is square
.海绵宝宝是方形的
[GROANING]
[呻吟]
.I'm ready, I'm ready-
.我准备好了，我准备好了-
.No, you ain't-
.不，你不是-
.I found Squarebob-
.我找到了Squarebob-
.That's just a cereal box-
.那只是一个麦片盒-
.Besides, he's yellow
.此外，他是黄色的
.Yeah, here he is-
.是的，他在这里-
?Hey, could I go home now
？嘿，我现在可以回家了吗
.Oh, look, he's up in the sky-
.哦，看，他在天上-
?Oh, he's not-- huh-
？哦，他不是——呵呵——
They must've gone
.to search some more
他们一定已经走了
.搜索更多
[COUGHING]
[咳嗽]
?Spongebob, where are you-
？海绵宝宝，你在哪里-
?You under there
？你在下面
.Nope
。没有
.Uh, I can explain-
.呃，我可以解释一下-
?Spongebob-
？海绵宝宝-
.Nope
。没有
?Spongebob, where are you
？海绵宝宝，你在哪里
.That squirrel's gone crazy-
.那只松鼠疯了-
But she'll never-
.look under a rock
但她永远不会——
.看看岩石下面
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.SPONGEBOB: You said it
.海绵宝宝：你说过了
.Sandy'll never find us
.桑迪永远找不到我们
.Eh
.呃
.Hey, wait, you don't understand
.嘿，等等，你不明白
,Oh, look, it is I, Spongebob-
.out here in the open
，哦，看，是我，海绵宝宝-
.在露天这里
?Spongebob-
？海绵宝宝-
!Ah-
！啊-
!Ah
！啊
.Come on, let me back in
.来吧，让我回来
.You don't understand
.你不明白
,Oh, Spongebob-
.I was so worried
，哦，海绵宝宝-
.我很担心
I thought something
.terrible happened
我想到了什么
.可怕的事情发生了
.Come on
。快点
There's just enough time
.to go atom smashing
时间刚好够用
.去原子粉碎
.Sandy, wait-
.桑迪，等等-
.There's no time to wait-
.没有时间等待-
!Hibernation
！冬眠
.Sandy, you gotta make time-
.桑迪，你得腾出时间-
.This is important
.这很重要
.I am a man
.我是一个男人
OK, Sandy, I-- I-- I-- I
.can't play with you anymore
好的，桑迪，我——我——我——我
.不能再陪你玩了
.I just can't take the games
.我就是无法接受游戏
.They're tearing me apart
.他们正在撕裂我
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
.There I said it
.我说了
Now, just promise we
.can still be friends
现在，我们只许承诺
.仍然可以是朋友
.Please, Sandy, this isn't easy
拜托，桑迪，这并不容易
--I
- 我
[SNORING]
[打鼾]
?SPONGEBOB: Sandy
?海绵宝宝：桑迪
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I never thought I'd say it, but
.thank Neptune for hibernation
我从没想过我会这么说，但是
.感谢海王星的冬眠
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[SNORING]
[打鼾]
?How are you people-
？你们好吗——
,ANNOUNCER (ON TV): And now
back to the Crustacean Crime
，播音员（电视上）：现在
回到甲壳类犯罪
.Theatre
。剧院
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
!Stop, thief-
！站住，小偷——
?Which way did he go-
？他去了哪条路-
.He went that way-
.他朝那条路走去-
.Let's get him boys-
.让我们把他抓起来吧男孩们-
.Curses, foiled again-
.诅咒，再次挫败-
What a no good eel in-
.the kelp that guy was
鳗鱼真不好——
.那家伙是海带
There ain't nothing
.worse than a thief
没有什么了
.比小偷还坏
Thieves need to be
.locked up forever
盗贼必须是
.永远锁起来
They should all be
strung up by their gills
他们都应该是
被他们的鳃吊起来
.and forced to breathe air
.并被迫呼吸空气
Buy, Mr. Krabs, what about-
?all the stuff you stole
买吧，蟹老板，怎么样——
？你偷的所有东西
?What do you mean-
？你是什么意思-
.Like that barrel-
.就像那个桶-
It says property
.of Salty Sea Farms
上面写着财产
.of 咸海农场
Oh, that's where I-
.rent me pickles from
噢，那就是我——
.租给我泡菜
?Are you renting the barrel too-
？你也租桶吗-
.Well, no-
.好吧，不-
?Then you bought it-
？然后你就买了-
.No-
。不-
?Then isn't that stealing-
？那这不是偷——
--Well, I, uh-
——嗯，我，呃——
What about this towel from-
?the Sizzling Spring Sauna
这条毛巾怎么样——
? 热泉桑拿
--Um, well, that's-
——嗯，嗯，那就是——
?And this Bikini Bell phone-
？还有这款比基尼贝尔手机-
--Well, I-
——嗯，我——
?And Sandy's hedge clippers-
？还有桑迪的树篱剪-
--Oh, they're um-
--哦，他们是-
?And Plankton's lawnmower-
？还有浮游生物的割草机-
--Well, he-
——嗯，他——
?Even Mrs. Puff's hair curlers-
？就连泡芙太太的卷发夹——
.That one was a gift-
.那是一份礼物-
Listen, all that staff
.is, uh, borrowed
听着，所有的工作人员
.是，呃，借来的
?Borrowed-
?借来的-
.Well, that's a relief
.嗯，这真是一种解脱
I thought you took it
.without permission
我以为你拿走了
.未经许可
.Ah, permission, shmermission-
.啊，许可，shmermission-
You can borrow anything you
want, anytime, as long as you
你可以借任何东西
想要，任何时候，只要你愿意
.get it back before it's missed
.在错过之前将其取回
?Everyone knows that, right
？每个人都知道，对吧
.BOTH: OK
.两者：好的
.All right, then-
.好吧，那么——
Hugs, you put in a
.hard day's work, boys
拥抱，你投入了
.辛苦了一天，孩子们
.But I don't work here-
.但我不在这里工作-
.See you later-
.稍后见-
.Oh, that was close one
.哦，那是接近的一个
SPONGEBOB: What do
?you want to do today
海绵宝宝：做什么
？今天你想做
.I don't know-
。我不知道-
?What do you want to do today
?今天你想做什么
I don't know, what do-
?you want to do today
我不知道，该怎么办-
？今天你想做
.I don't know-
。我不知道-
.What do you want to today
.今天你想要什么
.I don't know-
。我不知道-
?What do you want to do today
?今天你想做什么
[GASPS]
[喘气]
.I know what I want to do today-
.我知道我今天想做什么-
.I need some money
.我需要一些钱
.Aw
.噢
!Oh
！哦
.Oh
。哦
.I don't have any money
.我没有钱
Spongebob, I want a balloon
.really, really badly
海绵宝宝，我想要一个气球
.真的，真的很糟糕
.Really, really badly
.It's OK, Patrick-
.没关系，帕特里克-
There's lots of
money in the First
有很多
钱在第一
.National Bank of Spongebob
.海绵宝宝国家银行
!Follow me
！跟我来
.Uh oh, I'm broke too
.呃哦，我也破产了
Maybe we can borrow
.money from Squidward
也许我们可以借
.来自章鱼哥的钱
Wait, instead of-
,borrowing the money
等等，而不是——
,借钱
why don't we just
?borrow the balloon
我们为什么不只是
？借气球
!Yeah-
！是的-
!Like Mr. Krabs
！就像蟹老板一样
?It's just borrowing, right-
？只是借用吧——
Yeah, and borrowing-
is OK as long
是的，还有借——
只要
?as we bring it back, right
？当我们把它带回来时，对吧
.Right-
。正确的-
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.This is so great-
.这太棒了-
.We're gonna have so much fun-
.我们会玩得很开心-
First, we can run
.with the balloon
首先，我们可以运行
.与气球
Yeah, then we could go to-
.the beach with the balloon
是的，然后我们可以去-
.有气球的海滩
Yeah, then we could take a-
.bike ride with the balloon
是的，那么我们可以采取-
.带着气球骑自行车
Then we could go to the
,movies, and the arcade
然后我们就可以去
、电影和街机
,and the ice rink
.and the pizza shop
，还有溜冰场
.还有披萨店
And the moon, and the-
,sky, and then a car
还有月亮，还有——
，天空，然后是汽车
.behind the dumpster
.垃圾箱后面
.And the candy shop-
.还有糖果店-
.And then my backyard-
.然后是我的后院-
.And then in a plane-
.然后在飞机上-
.And over a rock-
.然后越过一块岩石-
.And under a hill-
.在一座小山下-
.And with a whale-
.还有鲸鱼-
!BOTH: We love borrowing
!BOTH：我们喜欢借钱
.It popped-
.它弹出了-
!BOTH: Ah
！ 两人：啊
How are we gonna return-
?it now, Spongebob
我们要怎样回去——
？现在，海绵宝宝
.I've got the pieces-
.我已经拿到了碎片-
.I got the air-
.我得到了空气-
.Hurry, put the pieces on-
.快点，把碎片放上-
.We popped the balloon
.我们戳破了气球
.We can't return it
.我们无法退货
.We're thieves
.我们是小偷
[UNINTELLIGIBLE YELLING]
[难以理解的叫喊声]
.We have to confess
.我们必须承认
?Confess-
？承认-
?Are you out of your mind
？你疯了吗？
Do you have any idea what
?they do to people like us
你知道什么吗
？他们对像我们这样的人做了
We're not talking about
some dumb mail fraud scheme
我们不是在谈论
一些愚蠢的邮件欺诈计划
,or hijacking here
!we stole a balloon
，或者在这里劫持
！我们偷了一个气球
And they're going
.lock us up forever
他们要去
.把我们永远锁起来
.You're right-
。你说得对-
We've just got to
.keep our heads
我们只需要做
.保持头脑清醒
.Act normal
.表现正常
[UNINTELLIGIBLE NOISES]
[难以理解的噪音]
.Wow, street performers-
.哇，街头艺人-
[CROWD CHEERING]
[人群欢呼]
!BOTH: It's not working
!BOTH: 不起作用
!Ah
！啊
.Hi, there-
。你好呀-
!BOTH: Ah
！ 两人：啊
Hey, don't you-
?want a free balloon
嘿，你不是——
？想要一个免费气球
.It's national free balloon day
.今天是全国免费气球日
.He's on to us-
.他正在对付我们-
It's not safe in-
.Bikini Bottom anymore
这里不安全——
.比基尼下装不再
We've gotta move fast
.and cover our tracks
我们必须快速行动
.并掩盖我们的踪迹
.I'm on it, Spongebob-
.我就这么做了，海绵宝宝-
.Take a last look, Patrick-
.最后看一眼，帕特里克-
.We can never go back
.我们再也回不去了
.Goodbye, Bikini Bottom-
.再见，比基尼泳裤-
We've only got ourselves and-
.what we can carry on our backs
我们只有我们自己，而且——
.我们可以背什么
.Yup-
。是的-
We're gonna have-
.to travel lighter
我们将会有-
.轻松出行
.PATRICK: I want to go home
.PATRICK：我想回家
.We can never go home, Pat-
.我们永远不能回家，帕特-
.We're wanted men
.我们是通缉犯
We'll spend the rest of
.our lives running, running
我们将用剩下的时间
.我们的生活奔跑，奔跑
But at least it's
.warm around the fire
但至少是
.围着火取暖
Hey, if we're underwater, how-
,can there be a-- I'm scared
嘿，如果我们在水下，怎么-
，有没有可能——我很害怕
.Spongebob
.海绵宝宝
.No more nice warm beds-
.不再有温暖的床-
?Huh-
？哈-
.No more Krabby Patties-
.不再有蟹黄饼-
?Huh-
？哈-
.No more getting mail-
.不再收到邮件-
.No more Gary
.不再有加里
.No more movies
.没有更多电影了
.No more Squidward
.不再有章鱼哥了
No more Sandy, or
.Pearl, or Mr. Krabs
不再有桑迪，或者
.珍珠，或蟹老板
!No more anything
！没有什么了
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
!I want ice cream-
！我想要冰淇淋-
But it doesn't have-
?to be all bad, right
但它没有——
？一切都很糟糕，对吧
I mean, at least
.we have each other
我的意思是，至少
.我们有彼此
.Yeah-
。是的-
And all that running is good-
,for your buns and thighs
所有跑步都是好的——
，为了你的发髻和大腿
?right
？正确的
.Yeah, buns and thighs-
.是啊，小圆面包和大腿-
?And the bitter cold-
？还有刺骨的寒冷——
?It's bracing, isn't it
？这是支撑，不是吗？
Yeah, maybe being-
.a felon can be fun
是的，也许是——
.重罪犯可以很有趣
.We can loosen our ties
.我们可以放松我们的联系
!Yeah-
！是的-
.And we could fly
.我们可以飞翔
!Yeah-
！是的-
!Ah
！啊
[CRASHES]
[崩溃]
SPONGEBOB: OK, we
.still can't do that
海绵宝宝：好的，我们
.还是做不到
.But we don't have to shave
.但我们不必刮胡子
.I'm way ahead of you, buddy-
.我远远领先于你，伙计-
.And you get to talk tough-
.而且你得说得很强硬-
This town ain't big
.enough for the two of us
这个小镇不大
.足够我们两个人使用
.Let me try-
.让我试试-
.Uh
.呃
.Hey, punk, he-he
.嘿，朋克，呵呵
,And the best part is-
,now that we're felons
，最好的部分是——
，既然我们是重罪犯
we don't have to return
.anything we borrow
我们不必返回
.我们借的任何东西
!BOTH: Yeah
！ 两人：是啊
.And we owe it all to you-
.我们把这一切都归功于你-
?What are you talking about-
？你在说什么-
Taking the balloon
.was your evil plan
拿气球
.是你的邪恶计划吗
Doh, I'm nothing-
.but a lot of talk
呵呵，我什么都不是——
.但是很多话
You're the one with
.the sticky fingers
你是那个与
.粘粘的手指
Aw, Patrick, you're the-
.best bad influence ever
噢，帕特里克，你是——
.有史以来最好的不良影响
.You, too-
。你也是-
I wish we had-
.something to eat though
我希望我们有-
.不过吃点东西
!Look what I've got-
！看看我有什么——
!Rectangles-
！矩形-
Not just any
.rectangles, candy bars
不只是任何
.矩形、直板
.Oh-
。哦-
All we have to do is make 'em-
.last the rest of our lives
我们所要做的就是让他们——
.持续我们的余生
.Thanks, Spongebob-
.谢谢，海绵宝宝-
.I think I'll eat it now
.我想我现在就吃它
.Ah
。啊
.I think I'll eat it now
.我想我现在就吃它
.Ow
.噢
.Oh
。哦
?Where'd my candy bar go
？我的棒棒糖去哪儿了
.I must've dropped it
.我一定是把它掉了
.You just ate it, Pat-
.你刚刚吃了它，帕特-
.It's all over your face
.全都在你脸上
?Where'd it go-
？它去哪儿了-
.I'm going to starve
.我要饿死了
?Where'd it go
?它去哪儿了
.I can't find it
.我找不到它
?Where could it possibly be
？它可能在哪里
!Aha
！啊哈
?What-
？什么-
.You stole my candy bar-
.你偷了我的棒棒糖-
.No, I didn't-
.不，我没有-
?Oh, so that's how it is, huh-
？哦，原来如此，呵呵——
.Once a thief, always a thief
.一朝为贼，终生为贼
.You ate yours-
.你吃了你的-
.This is mine
.这是我的
.You took my only food-
.你拿走了我唯一的食物-
.Now I'm gonna starve
.现在我要饿死了
Here, Patrick, just-
.take half of mine
在这里，帕特里克，只是——
.拿我的一半
?Yours-
？你的-
.You mean mine
.你是说我的
?Do you want it or what-
？你想要它还是什么-
I don't want it unless-
.you admit you took it
我不想要它，除非——
.你承认你拿走了它
.This is my candy bar-
.这是我的棒棒糖-
.Liar, liar, plants for hire-
.骗子，骗子，出租植物-
.It's pants on fire, Patrick-
.裤子着火了，帕特里克-
.Well, you would know, liar-
.好吧，你会知道的，骗子-
Well, if you're gonna be-
.that way, I'll eat it myself
好吧，如果你要——
.这样我就自己吃
.You better not-
.你最好不要-
.I'm warning you
.我警告你
.Ah-
。啊-
!Don't-
！不-
!Stop it
！停下来
!Don't
！不
!Oh
！哦
!Ah
！啊
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
!Ah
！啊
.Mhm-
.嗯-
.You're a crazy person-
.你是个疯狂的人-
I should've expected this after
.the way you stole that balloon
我应该预料到这一点
.你偷气球的方式
?Did I, Patrick-
？我是吗，帕特里克——
?Did I
？我有吗？
Or did your criminal mind
?hypnotise me to steal it
还是你的犯罪心理
？催眠我偷它
!Oh-
！哦-
.That's it
。就是这样
!Ah
！啊
.First, the balloon
.一、气球
.Now, my candy bar
.现在，我的棒棒糖
.You're out of control
.你失控了
.I-- I'm telling on you
.我--我在告诉你
.Not if I tell on you first-
.如果我先告发你就不会-
.I'll beat you there-
.我会在那里打败你-
.You're gonna get in trouble-
.你会遇到麻烦的-
.No, you are-
.不，你是——
[PANTING]
[气喘吁吁]
?What can I do for you boys-
？我能为你们做些什么-
!BOTH: We stole a balloon
!BOTH：我们偷了一个气球
[CRYING]
[哭泣]
?What's the problem here-
？这里有什么问题-
Well, it appears these-
.two stole a balloon
嗯，看来这些——
.两个偷了一个气球
?What are you going to do to us-
？你要对我们做什么-
[WHISPERING]
[耳语]
.OK, follow me-
.好吧，跟我来-
If you can't do the
.time, don't do the crime
如果你做不到
.时间，不要犯罪
.OK, time's up
.好的，时间到了
.Now, get out
.现在，出去吧
.But-- but we stole a balloon-
.但是--但是我们偷了一个气球-
.Yeah, on free balloon day-
.是的，在免费气球日-
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
How about some lollipops-
?for the road, boys
来点棒棒糖怎么样——
？为了路上，孩子们
Let's vow never-
to borrow anything
我们发誓永不——
借东西
.without permission again
.再次未经许可
.You said it-
.你说过-
All right, which one of you
?flatfoots stole my lollipop
好吧，你们哪一个
？扁平足偷了我的棒棒糖
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
.SPONGEBOB: Oh, brother
.海绵宝宝：噢，兄弟
.PATRICK: I mean it
.PATRICK：我是认真的
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]